# Scott E. Roberts

Email: s.e.roberts0@gmail.com | Personal Website: https://scotteroberts.github.io GitHub: https://www.github.com/ScotteRoberts | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-e-roberts

## **OBJECTIVE**

Currently seeking a junior developer / junior software engineer position in hopes of creating long-lasting, secure solutions that improve the lives of users. Three years of experience in object-oriented programming. Acquired skills developing secure, extensible, and scalable solutions while following the Agile software design principles using Scrum.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: C#, Java, SQL, ES6, Python, C++

Environments: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Xcode, NetBeans, Anaconda Spyder

Frameworks: .NET, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, Vue.js, Bulma

Tools: GitHub, Terminal, PowerShell, Google Suite, Trello, Slack, Axosoft, GitKraken

## **PROJECTS**

Team Lead | Web Application | Software Engineering Senior Project

Sep. 2017 – May 2018

- Led a team of 6 developers following the Agile methodology and implemented a deployable single page application (SPA) that collected and stored internet articles via web crawling to guarantee a safe environment for users to learn at their leisure
- Integrated with a mock Single Sign On service to simplify user authentication and promote awareness of other company applications
- Improved team velocity by at least 15% each sprint by enforcing daily standups using Google Suite

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Engineering Intern** | Enterprise Portfolio Software

May 2017 – Aug. 2017

 Communicated internationally via Skype with a software engineer to improve the UI/UX for a proprietary project management web application

**Director** | California Junior Lifeguard Programs Inc.

Jun. 2016 – Aug. 2017

- Led 60-100 children (6 15 years old) and 10-15 Instructors during an all-day summer camp by enforcing proper safety protocols and creating efficient daily agendas for multiple age groups which resulted in a safer, organized camp environment
- Communicated directly with parents on camp costs, upgrade fees, and children's behavior to ensure customer satisfaction and inclusion into camp activities
- Maintained an average 50% return rate of participants by including old activities for mastery
  of skills and designing new, engaging activities to preserve camp interest

Instructor | California Junior Lifeguard Programs Inc.

Jun. 2011 – Aug. 2015

Graduated: May 2018

- Reduced potential injuries by identifying potential victims and hazards on land and water and responded to life-threatening situations through prepared Emergency Action Plans
- Educated children in teamwork, physical fitness, lifesaving skills, and oceanography through
  physical activities and group lectures which improved participants respectfulness toward
  leadership and peers and encouraged community awareness

#### **EDUCATION**